{"category":"music","correctAnswer":"Neil Diamond","incorrectAnswers":["Leonard Cohen","Paul McCartney","David Bowie"],"question":"Whose 1973 Album Was Titled \"Jonathan Livingston Seagull\"?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"geography","correctAnswer":"Istanbul","incorrectAnswers":["Rome","Moscow","Athens"],"question":"The Hagia Sophia is an iconic structure in what city?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"general_knowledge","correctAnswer":"Aqueducts","incorrectAnswers":["Canals","Pipelines","Trenches"],"question":"What type of structures are used to conduct a water stream across a valley?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"general_knowledge","correctAnswer":"Three Gorges Dam","incorrectAnswers":["Grand Coulee Dam","Hoover Dam","Oroville Dam"],"question":"What is the worlds longest concrete dam?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"history","correctAnswer":"American Civil War","incorrectAnswers":["World War I","The Cold War","French invasion of Russia"],"question":"What event began on April 12, 1861?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"film_and_tv","correctAnswer":"In the future, a small waste-collecting robot inadvertently embarks on a space journey.","incorrectAnswers":["On a journey to find the cure for a curse, a boy finds himself in the middle of a war.","After a mathematician accepts secret work in cryptography, his life takes a turn for the nightmarish.","In a post-apocalyptic wasteland, a woman rebels against a tyrannical ruler."],"question":"What is the plot of the movie WALL·E?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"film_and_tv","correctAnswer":"The Wolf of Wall Street","incorrectAnswers":["Django Unchained","Up","Snatch"],"question":"Name the movie that matches the following plot summary: 'Follows the rise and fall of a stock-broker living the high life.'","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"film_and_tv","correctAnswer":"Marion Cotillard","incorrectAnswers":["Cate Blanchett","Julie Christie","Laura Linney"],"question":"Who won the 2007 Academy Award for Best Leading Actress for playing the role of Edith Piaf in La Vie en Rose?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"society_and_culture","correctAnswer":"Jim Jones","incorrectAnswers":["Walter White","Tim Thompson","Mark Matthews"],"question":"Who founded the People's Temple Commune?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"arts_and_literature","correctAnswer":"Romanticism","incorrectAnswers":["Realism","Nostalgia","Kunboism"],"question":"Which artistic movement of the late eighteenth to mid-nineteenth century focused on emotion over reason, and on spontaneous expression.","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"music","correctAnswer":"The Beatles","incorrectAnswers":["Deep Purple","Feeder","Uriah Heep"],"question":"Which English rock band released the studio album 'Help!'?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"film_and_tv","correctAnswer":"A warthog","incorrectAnswers":["A lion","An elephant","A rhinoceros"],"question":"In the Lion King, what sort of animal is Pumbaa?","difficulty":"easy"},{"category":"arts_and_literature","correctAnswer":"Thomas Mann","incorrectAnswers":["Franz Kafka","Johann Wolfgang von Goethe","Hermann Hesse"],"question":"Who is the German author of Buddenbrooks?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"music","correctAnswer":"Michael Jackson","incorrectAnswers":["Nicki Minaj","Neil Young","Eric Clapton"],"question":"Which American singer released the song 'Wanna Be Startin' Somethin''?","difficulty":"easy"},{"category":"film_and_tv","correctAnswer":"1995","incorrectAnswers":["1987","1991","1999"],"question":"In which year was Seven first released in the cinema?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"food_and_drink","correctAnswer":"Melba Toast ","incorrectAnswers":["Sourdough","Tiger Bread","Rye Bread"],"question":"Which Type Of Prepared Bread Is Named After An Opera Singer?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"history","correctAnswer":"Soviet Union","incorrectAnswers":["France","Mexico","Brazil"],"question":"With what country did the US almost start a war during the Cuban Missile Crisis?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"music","correctAnswer":"Rockwell","incorrectAnswers":["The Verve","Big Country","Deee-Lite"],"question":"'Somebody's Watching Me' was a one hit wonder in 1984 by which artist?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"general_knowledge","correctAnswer":"Non-player character","incorrectAnswers":["New player character","Non-playable challenge","Never play cautiously"],"question":"In video game slang, what does the acronym 'NPC' stand for?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"food_and_drink","correctAnswer":"Caramelization","incorrectAnswers":["Frying","Boiling","Blanching"],"question":"What cooking process involves cooking ingredients containing sugar on a low heat to alter the flavour and color?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"film_and_tv","correctAnswer":"Russell Crowe","incorrectAnswers":["Seth Rogen","John Wayne","Ron Perlman"],"question":"Which actor has starred in films including Gladiator and Man of Steel?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"general_knowledge","correctAnswer":"A bathtub","incorrectAnswers":["A shower","A sink","A toilet"],"question":"What type of item might you have as a clawfoot in your bathroom?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"sport_and_leisure","correctAnswer":"Dallas Mavericks","incorrectAnswers":["Dallas Eathquakes","Dallas Yankees","Dallas Football"],"question":"Which of these is a basketball team based in Dallas?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"geography","correctAnswer":"Boston","incorrectAnswers":["Austin","Atlanta","Philadelphia"],"question":"In which US city is Beacon Street?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"geography","correctAnswer":"Three equal horizontal bands of red white and black, with a gold eagle in the center.","incorrectAnswers":["White with a blue star centered between two equal horizontal blue bands","Red with a black two headed eagle in the center.","Three horizontal bands of maroon white and maroon."],"question":"What does the flag of Egypt look like?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"music","correctAnswer":"Joni Mitchell","incorrectAnswers":["Cher","Beyoncé","Grace Jones"],"question":"Whose Real Name Is Roberta Anderson?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"history","correctAnswer":"Operation Husky","incorrectAnswers":["Operation Overlord","Operation Barbarossa","Operation Market Garden"],"question":"What was the name of the Allied invasion of Sicily in 1943?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"geography","correctAnswer":"Brazil","incorrectAnswers":["Peru","Ecuador","Suriname"],"question":"Which of these countries borders Argentina?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"geography","correctAnswer":"South","incorrectAnswers":["East","West","North"],"question":"What direction comes before \"Sudan\" in the name of a country in Africa?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"society_and_culture","correctAnswer":"Seneca the Younger","incorrectAnswers":["Thomas Hobbes","Denis Diderot","Ludwig Wittgenstein"],"question":"Which philosopher famously said 'Virtue is nothing else than right reason'?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"film_and_tv","correctAnswer":"Jet Li","incorrectAnswers":["Kenneth Branagh","Luke Evans","Stephen Fry"],"question":"Which actor has played roles in both The Expendables and Mulan?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"sport_and_leisure","correctAnswer":"Alf Ramsey","incorrectAnswers":["Oliver Stanton","Glenn Hoddle","Jack Dorsey"],"question":"In 1974 who was sacked from his position of England football manager?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"sport_and_leisure","correctAnswer":"Football","incorrectAnswers":["Track and field","Badminton","Boxing"],"question":"With which sport is Lionel Messi associated?","difficulty":"easy"},{"category":"food_and_drink","correctAnswer":"Avocado","incorrectAnswers":["Mango","Banana","Pineapple"],"question":"Which fruit has the most calories per gram?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"film_and_tv","correctAnswer":"Diane Keaton","incorrectAnswers":["Anne Bancroft","Jane Fonda","Shirley MacLaine"],"question":"Who won the 1977 Academy Award for Best Leading Actress for playing the role of Annie Hall in Annie Hall?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"geography","correctAnswer":"Kenya","incorrectAnswers":["Colombia","Georgia","Uzbekistan"],"question":"Nairobi is the capital city of which country?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"food_and_drink","correctAnswer":"Chutney","incorrectAnswers":["Salsa","Pesto","Hummus"],"question":"What is the name of the popular relishes of spices and fruits that often accompany Indian foods?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"geography","correctAnswer":"Italy","incorrectAnswers":["China","Belgium","Argentina"],"question":"In which country would you find the Dolomites?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"music","correctAnswer":"Miles Davis","incorrectAnswers":["Leonard Cohen","Jerry Lee Lewis","Jay Z"],"question":"Whose Albums Include \"Kind Of Blue\", \"In A Silent Way\", \"Bitches Bru\" & \"Tutu\"?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"society_and_culture","correctAnswer":"One of the main writers of the New Testament.","incorrectAnswers":["The first pope.","Missionary responsibile for spreading Christianity to East Asia. ","One of the main characters of the Protestant Reformation. "],"question":"Which of the following describes St. Paul?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"geography","correctAnswer":"Brooklyn","incorrectAnswers":["Queens","Manhattan","Bronx"],"question":"Flatbush and Flatlands are neighborhoods located in which New York City borough?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"music","correctAnswer":"Ringo Starr","incorrectAnswers":["Ricky Martin","Kanye West","Bob Marley"],"question":"How in the world of music is Richard Starkey more commonly known?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"history","correctAnswer":"Parthenon","incorrectAnswers":["Colosseum","Vivarium","Academy"],"question":"Which of these is a building in the acropolis of Athens?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"music","correctAnswer":"You Light Up My Life","incorrectAnswers":["Don't Wanna Fall in Love","The Hustle","Cars"],"question":"Debby Boone had a one hit wonder in 1977 with which song?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"film_and_tv","correctAnswer":"1992","incorrectAnswers":["1980","1984","1988"],"question":"Reservoir Dogs was released in which year?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"society_and_culture","correctAnswer":"Think Different","incorrectAnswers":["Just Do It","I'm Lovin' It","Got Milk?"],"question":"After rejoining Apple in 1997, Steve Jobs engineered what ad campaign?","difficulty":"easy"},{"category":"sport_and_leisure","correctAnswer":"Athletics","incorrectAnswers":["Badminton","Motor racing","Basketball"],"question":"With which sport is Emil Zatopek associated?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"arts_and_literature","correctAnswer":"Dr Zhivago","incorrectAnswers":["Lolita","The Brothers Karamazov","The Cherry Orchard"],"question":"For which novel was Boris Pasternak awarded the 1958 Nobel Prize, an award he declined?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"society_and_culture","correctAnswer":"The Trojan War","incorrectAnswers":["The Hundred Years' War","The Peloponnesian War","The Punic Wars"],"question":"According to legend, refugees of which 1200 B.C. conflict first fled to Thrace, then north Africa and finally Italy?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"science","correctAnswer":"A Vixen","incorrectAnswers":["A Ewe","A Hen","A Doe"],"question":"What is the word for a female fox?","difficulty":"easy"},{"category":"geography","correctAnswer":"Two equal horizontal bands of white and red.","incorrectAnswers":["Maroon with a broad white serrated band on the left side.","Three equal vertical bands of green, yellow, and red.","Three equal horizontal bands of green white and red."],"question":"What does the flag of Poland look like?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"film_and_tv","correctAnswer":"\"As God is my witness, I'll never be hungry again.\"","incorrectAnswers":["\"With great power comes great responsiblity.\"","\"Forget it, Jake, it's Chinatown.\"","\"I am Groot.\""],"question":"Which of these quotes is from the film 'Gone with the Wind'?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"sport_and_leisure","correctAnswer":"Horse Racing","incorrectAnswers":["Swimming","Rugby","Golf"],"question":"What sport would you associate with The Kentucky Derby?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"sport_and_leisure","correctAnswer":"Basketball","incorrectAnswers":["Volleyball","Football","Baseball"],"question":"What Sport Do The Harlem Globetrotters Play?","difficulty":"easy"},{"category":"food_and_drink","correctAnswer":"Huevos Rancheros","incorrectAnswers":["Enchiladas","Tacos","Burritos"],"question":"What famous Mexican dish consists of eggs served on tortillas and topped with salsa?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"geography","correctAnswer":"Phnom Penh","incorrectAnswers":["Dhaka","Luanda","Apia"],"question":"What is the capital city of Cambodia?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"sport_and_leisure","correctAnswer":"Blue","incorrectAnswers":["Yellow","Purple","Red"],"question":"In a nine-ball pool set what colour is the number 2 ball?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"sport_and_leisure","correctAnswer":"Cincinnati Bengals","incorrectAnswers":["Cincinnati Mariners","Cincinnati Cavaliers","Cincinnati FC"],"question":"Which of these is an American Football team based in Cincinnati?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"geography","correctAnswer":"Mumbai","incorrectAnswers":["Sydney","Taipei","Yokohama"],"question":"Which of these cities is in India?","difficulty":"easy"},{"category":"music","correctAnswer":"Bob Dylan","incorrectAnswers":["Neil Young","Eric Clapton","Alanis Morissette"],"question":"Which American musician released the song 'Times They Are a-Changin''?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"food_and_drink","correctAnswer":"Wrapped in pastry","incorrectAnswers":["Stuffed with meat","Eaten raw","Served with melted cheese"],"question":"In cooking does the French term 'en croute' mean?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"science","correctAnswer":"HTTPS","incorrectAnswers":["FTP","SSH","SMTP"],"question":"Which networking protocol is used to access websites securely?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"society_and_culture","correctAnswer":"Hermes","incorrectAnswers":["Apollo","Mercury","Artemis"],"question":"Who is the Greek messenger god?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"science","correctAnswer":"A herd","incorrectAnswers":["A sounder","A host","A pack"],"question":"What is the word for a group of ponies?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"food_and_drink","correctAnswer":"Iceland","incorrectAnswers":["The Czech Republic","Austria","Nepal"],"question":"Which country is associated with the drink brennivín?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"society_and_culture","correctAnswer":"Winston Churchill","incorrectAnswers":["Aristotle","Jean Paul Sartre","Karl Marx"],"question":"Who described Russia as 'a riddle wrapped in a mystery inside an enigma'?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"society_and_culture","correctAnswer":"Divining Rods","incorrectAnswers":["Feng Shui Rods","Geomancy Sticks","Magnetic Field Sensors"],"question":"What are the forked sticks sometimes used to locate water, dismissed by scientists as superstition?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"society_and_culture","correctAnswer":"Afroasiatic","incorrectAnswers":["Japonic","Turkic","Indo-European"],"question":"The language 'Hejazi Arabic' belongs to which language family?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"film_and_tv","correctAnswer":"Emma Thompson","incorrectAnswers":["Kirsten Dunst","Charlize Theron","Sandra Bæ Hovedr"],"question":"Which actress has appeared in both Beauty and the Beast and Men in Black 3?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"science","correctAnswer":"Thomas Edison","incorrectAnswers":["Samuel Colt","Henry Blair","Elisha Otis"],"question":"Who Invented The Gramophone?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"geography","correctAnswer":"Nova Scotia","incorrectAnswers":["Prince Edward Island","New Brunswick","Quebec"],"question":"In which Canadian province is Halifax?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"general_knowledge","correctAnswer":"Erf","incorrectAnswers":["Billingsgate","Taradiddle","Blatherskite"],"question":"Which word is defined as 'a plot of land'?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"society_and_culture","correctAnswer":"Azul","incorrectAnswers":["Blau","Blauw","Blanco"],"question":"What is the Spanish word for 'blue'?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"science","correctAnswer":"Foot","incorrectAnswers":["Hand","Spine","Skull"],"question":"Which part of the human body has 26 bones, including 7 tarsals?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"arts_and_literature","correctAnswer":"Nikolai Gogol","incorrectAnswers":["Virginia Woolf","Alexander Pushkin","Ayn Rand"],"question":"Which author wrote 'Evenings on a Farm Near Dikanka'?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"film_and_tv","correctAnswer":"Catch Me If You Can","incorrectAnswers":["American History X","Logan","American Beauty"],"question":"Name the movie that matches the following plot summary: 'A skilled forger and conman is pursued by an FBI agent.'","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"film_and_tv","correctAnswer":"David Cronenberg","incorrectAnswers":["Baz Luhrmann","Alfred Hitchcock","Peter Jackson"],"question":"Which director's films included Shivers, Videodrome and The Fly?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"history","correctAnswer":"A privateer","incorrectAnswers":["A corsair","A buccaneer","A sea wolf"],"question":"What was the term used for a pirate who was licensed by the crown to capture enemy ships and cargo?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"film_and_tv","correctAnswer":"A Streetcar Named Desire","incorrectAnswers":["Saturday Night Fever","Sunset Boulevard","Wall Street"],"question":"Which film contains the character 'Stanley Kowalski'?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"music","correctAnswer":"The Beatles","incorrectAnswers":["Deep Purple","Feeder","Uriah Heep"],"question":"Which English rock band released the song 'Yellow Submarine'?","difficulty":"easy"},{"category":"science","correctAnswer":"Control","incorrectAnswers":["Test","Experimental","Base"],"question":"In experiments, what is the name of the group that does not receive the treatment?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"music","correctAnswer":"David Bowie","incorrectAnswers":["Eric Clapton","Madonna","Freddie Mercury"],"question":"Which British musician released the album 'The Rise and Fall of Ziggy Stardust and the Spiders from Mars'?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"geography","correctAnswer":"Kabul","incorrectAnswers":["Baghdad","Damascus","Tripoli"],"question":"What is the capital city of Afghanistan?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"geography","correctAnswer":"Antigua and Barbuda","incorrectAnswers":["New Zealand","South Africa","Jordan"],"question":"Saint John's is the capital city of which country?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"society_and_culture","correctAnswer":"Praesis ut prosis ne ut imperes","incorrectAnswers":["Libertas perfundet omnia luce","Non loqui sed facere","Carpe diem"],"question":"Which of these Latin phrases means 'Lead in order to serve, not in order to rule'?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"music","correctAnswer":"The Who","incorrectAnswers":["Deep Purple","Travis","Spandau Ballet"],"question":"Which English rock band released the album 'Quadrophenia'?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"science","correctAnswer":"Spinosaurus","incorrectAnswers":["Tyrannosaurus Rex","Giganotosaurus","Allosaurus"],"question":"Which dinosaur was the largest carnivore?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"society_and_culture","correctAnswer":"Democratic Republic of the Congo","incorrectAnswers":["Angola","Pakistan","Sri Lanka"],"question":"Swahili is a language spoken in which of these countries?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"arts_and_literature","correctAnswer":"Stanza","incorrectAnswers":["Sonnet","Meter","Rhyme"],"question":"What is another name for a single verse of a poem?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"society_and_culture","correctAnswer":"Negen","incorrectAnswers":["Neuf","Nove","Zes"],"question":"In Dutch, what is the word for for 'nine'?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"film_and_tv","correctAnswer":"Jonah Hill","incorrectAnswers":["Javier Bardem","Hugo Weaving","Warwick Davis"],"question":"Which actor has appeared in both Django Unchained and The Wolf of Wall Street?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"food_and_drink","correctAnswer":"Fermentation","incorrectAnswers":["Distillation","Oxidation","Clarification"],"question":"What is the process used to convert grape juice into wine called?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"history","correctAnswer":"Hieroglyphics","incorrectAnswers":["The Enigma Machine","Linear B","RSA Encryption"],"question":"What Was Deciphered As A Result Of The Discovery Of The Rosetta Stone?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"food_and_drink","correctAnswer":"Ireland","incorrectAnswers":["Romania","Mongolia","Finland"],"question":"In which country is guinness a popular drink?","difficulty":"easy"},{"category":"music","correctAnswer":"Stringed","incorrectAnswers":["Percussion","Woodwind","Brass"],"question":"What type of instrument is a lute?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"music","correctAnswer":"One Direction","incorrectAnswers":["Level 42","Orchestral Manoeuvres in the Dark","Blur"],"question":"Which English-Irish boy band released the song 'One Way or Another (Teenage Kicks)'?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"film_and_tv","correctAnswer":"Schindler's List","incorrectAnswers":["The Bridge on the River Kwai","One Flew Over the Cuckoo's Nest","Eternal Sunshine of the Spotless Mind"],"question":"Name the movie that matches the following plot summary: 'A man becomes concerned for his Jewish workforce after witnessing their persecution by the Nazis.'","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"film_and_tv","correctAnswer":"Quentin Beck","incorrectAnswers":["Obadiah Stane","James \"Rhodey\" Rhodes","Dr. Hank Pym"],"question":"Jake Gyllenhaal plays the role of which character in the Marvel Cinematic Universe?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"arts_and_literature","correctAnswer":"Malvolio","incorrectAnswers":["Hamlet","Polonius","Gertrude"],"question":"Which of the following characters is not in 'Hamlet'?","difficulty":"hard"},